I'm going to tell you about my private life.
我要跟大家讲讲我的私人生活。
I've had some good news recently, is that I've got…
我最近有个好消息，就是我……
My wife has always had a dream, OK, to own a little place in the countryside, and it became my dream when she told me about it every day for ten years.
我妻子一直有一个梦想，就是在乡下拥有一处小房子。而在她连续十年每天都跟我提这件事之后，它也变成了我的梦想。
And recently I bought a little place in the countryside for us, beautiful little place, it's very remote, very isolated, very private, rolling hills, it's surrounded by a farm, it's not our farm, but it's just lovely.
最近，我终于给我们买了一处乡间小屋。那里特别漂亮，位置偏远、与世隔绝、非常私密，四周是连绵起伏的山丘，还被一座农场环绕——虽然农场不是我们的，但整个地方真的美极了。
We didn't tell the children we were getting it.
我们没有提前告诉孩子们要买这座房子。
It was the most magical day when we first moved in, and we were standing outside, all of us, my children, running around in the fields, they couldn't believe it, giggling, and the sun going down, and my wife and I holding hands, going, we did it, it's amazing, I'm so happy, and tears, it was beautiful.
我们第一次搬进去的那天，是我人生中最梦幻的一天。我们一家人站在屋外，孩子们在田野里跑来跑去，笑个不停，简直不敢相信这一切。夕阳缓缓落下，我和妻子牵着手，不停地说："我们做到了，太不可思议了，我太幸福了。" 我们甚至感动得流下了眼泪，那一刻真的太美好了。
And lovely little animals, little birds, cos you don't see little birds in London, you know.
还有各种可爱的小动物、小鸟，因为在伦敦你几乎看不到这些小鸟。
In London we had pigeons, sort of suicidal pigeons, sort of come in front of the car, just look at you, kill me, end of my life, it's not worth it.
在伦敦，我们看到的只有鸽子，而且还是那种"自杀式"的鸽子，突然飞到车前，盯着你，好像在说："撞死我吧，我的人生已经没有意义了。"
And they just fly off at the last second, I don't even have the guts to end it!
结果总是在最后一秒飞走，好像在说："我连结束自己的勇气都没有！"
And all these multicoloured birds coming out of the woods, like they were welcoming us to the country, making lovely noises.
然后各种五彩斑斓的小鸟从树林里飞出来，仿佛在欢迎我们来到乡村，还发出悦耳的叫声。
Like they were saying, hello, welcome, thank you, thank you for coming.
仿佛它们在说："你好，欢迎你们，谢谢你们来到这里。"
My wife holding hands, children running around, lovely.
我和妻子牵着手，孩子们四处奔跑，一切都那么美好。
Then the sun went down completely.
然后太阳彻底落山了。
Absolute, total darkness.
四周一片漆黑。
Pitch black, terrified.
黑得伸手不见五指，我们吓坏了。
We both looked at where we thought we were.
我们俩朝着自己以为对方所在的位置看去。
Darling, are you there? I can't even see you. "
亲爱的，你在那儿吗？我连你都看不见了。"
We should go to London, we can't do this, can we? "
我们还是回伦敦吧，这种日子我们过不了，对吧？Where are the children? Children! " 孩子们呢？孩子们！"
And it was like all those lovely daytime animals were instantly replaced by the night shift animals.
仿佛白天那些可爱的小动物，一瞬间全都被"夜班动物"取代了。
Noises from birds I'd never heard before.
各种我从来没听过的鸟叫声。
Sinister sounds.
阴森恐怖的声音。
I actually googled what bird sounds like a child screaming in the woods.
我甚至真的去 Google 搜索："什么鸟叫起来像树林里有小孩在尖叫？"
Seriously. There was just this…
真的。 当时就只有这种声音……
That was it.
就是那样。
My whole family holding hands in a 360, edging to where we hoped the house was.  I want to go home!
我们全家手牵着手围成一圈，小心翼翼地一点一点挪向我们希望是房子的方向。 我要回家！
We're drifting into the neighbour's fields. And foxes.
我们都快漂到邻居家的田里去了。 还有狐狸。
In London, when you see a fox, you see it for a second and you just go, "Oh, look, there's a fox," and then it disappears, like into thin air.
在伦敦，你看到狐狸时，它通常只出现一秒钟，你说一句"哦，有只狐狸"，它就像凭空消失了一样。
In the country, you hear the noises they make.
可是在乡下，你能听见它们发出的声音。
They make this vile sort of…
它们会发出一种特别恶心的声音……
Like they're vomiting violently.
就像在拼命呕吐一样。
There was this fox just walking towards us. ⏩
有一只狐狸正朝我们走过来。
Cats. Pussycats.
还有猫。小猫咪。
On heat.
发情了。
Is there a more sinister sound out there than a cat sort of whining?
还有什么声音能比发情的猫叫更阴森吗？
If only women were like this, how much easier would my teenage years have been?
要是女人也像这样就好了，那我的青春期该轻松多少啊。
I think Beverly's up for it. "
我觉得 Beverly 有意思。" / "我觉得 Beverly 愿意。"
I think you're right, Dave, leave me to it. " ⏩
我觉得你说得对，Dave，这事交给我吧。"
Finally, we made it into the house.
最后，我们总算进了屋。
You know, people in the country, they say things like, "We never lock our doors in the country."
乡下的人总喜欢说："我们这里从来不锁门。"
Are you joking?
开什么玩笑？
I was putting furniture in front of the door.
我都已经开始搬家具堵门了。
I opened the curtains to see what it was like.
我拉开窗帘，想看看外面是什么情况。
It was a fox in my face.
结果一只狐狸就在我眼前。
Oh, my God, it's getting worse!
天哪，情况越来越糟了！
Cos the fear is someone's going to break in at night.
因为最可怕的是，有人晚上会闯进来。
What are you going to do if someone breaks in in the countryside?
如果有人在乡下闯进你家，你怎么办？
In London, you tell them where you live, you tell them your road, your postcode, the number, then the police will come to your house.
在伦敦，你只要告诉警方你住哪条街、邮编、门牌号，他们就能找到你家。
In the country, people say things like, "Ignore the postcode, that takes you to another house."
可是在乡下，人们会说："别看邮编，那个会把你导航到别人家。"
Or, "Why don't you swap postcodes with that house?"
或者："你干脆和那户人家交换邮编吧。"
Every house just has names. The Glebe House, the Rectory, the little cottage on the hill.
每栋房子都只有名字。 比如"Glebe House""The Rectory""山坡上的小屋"之类的名字。
I've just spent my whole life giving people directions.
我感觉自己这辈子都在给别人指路。
There's a dip, there's a dip in the road, you'll feel it, you won't see it, you'll feel a slight dip. "
路上有一个下坡，你会感觉得到，但你看不出来，就是一个轻微的起伏。"
There's some roadkill, it used to be there, there might be some roadkill, there's a left, there's a sharp left. "
路边以前有一只路杀动物，也许现在还有；接着左转，再来一个急左转。"
You think you're driving into a hedge, you've got to trust it's there, you've got to trust it's there. "
你会觉得自己要直接开进树篱里了，但你得相信路就在那儿，真的得相信。"
Then you'll be on a lane for about a mile, then you'll come to a huge oak tree.
然后你会沿着一条乡间小路开一英里左右，接着会看到一棵巨大的橡树。
Then you know you've gone too far, you must turn back and go, "For God's sake!"
然后你就知道自己开过头了，只能掉头，嘴里还得骂一句："我的天哪！"
You can't be saying this to the police on the phone.
你总不能在电话里这样给警察指路吧。
You might as well pass it on to the burglar.
你还不如直接把地址告诉小偷算了。
How did you find the place? "
你是怎么找到这里的？"
Can I put you on? "
我能把电话转给你吗？"（这里是脱口秀里的调侃说法）
Because the onus is on us as men. This is what my wife does.
因为作为男人，这种责任都落在我们身上。 我妻子总是这样。
Every time there's a noise in the house, she wakes me up.
每次家里一有动静，她就把我叫醒。
In bed, she's like, "Did you hear that?"
躺在床上，她就会说："你听见了吗？"
Coming from the kitchen, did you hear that noise? "
厨房那边传来的，你听见那个声音了吗？"
And I always deny it, even though I've heard it, because I'm awake, terrified.
而我总是否认，哪怕我明明听见了，因为我已经醒着，而且吓坏了。
No, no, it must be the wind, even though I know there's no wind in the kitchen. "
没有没有，肯定是风。" 尽管我知道厨房里根本没有风。
She always says the same thing, "Go and see."
她每次都说同一句话："去看看。"
Go on, go downstairs and see. "
快去，下楼看看。"
I'm always like, "Well, that wasn't exactly the way I was going to handle this situation."
我心想："嗯，这可不是我原本打算处理这件事的方法。"
I was hoping we would hide as a family…
我原本希望我们一家人一起躲起来……
…and await rescue. ……
然后等待救援。
But, Michael, you're the man of the house. "
可是，Michael，你是一家之主啊。"
Yes, you're right, I am the man of the house, but what concerns me at this very moment is I think there's another man in the house. "
没错，你说得对，我确实是一家之主。但我现在真正担心的是——我觉得屋里还有另一个男人。"
And I've decided to make him the man of the house on this occasion.
所以这一次，我决定让他来当一家之主。
But what about the children? "
那孩子们怎么办？"
Good idea, send one of them, send the older one, the nine-year-old. "
好主意，派一个去吧，就派大的那个，九岁的那个。"